Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to create a moving platform.
To get started, just select our platform blueprint.
Right click and go duplicate.
And call this ah, moving platform.
If we just open this up and go over to components and go ahead and look for interrupt movement, this
will add a type of movement to our moving platform.
Just select it and go over to control and add two elements.
These control points basically represent the points that are moving.
Platform is going to move between.
So we've added two because we're going to have this moving platform move between two points.
Next, we want to go over to behavior type and just change this to be ping pong.
What this will basically mean is our moving platform will ping pong between these two control points.
So go to control point zero, then control point one, and then back to there and then back to one.
If I change this to something like one chop, what that basically mean is when I'm moving platform moves,
it will move from platforms to platform one and then just stop.
You can hover over each behavior type to see more about what it does.
But we want to work with the ping pong one.
Next, we want to create two new variables.
Cool.
This first one location one and undesirable type to be a vector because this variable is going to basically
represent where our moving platform is going to move.
Make sure that this variable is instance editable and you have show three D widget.
Then create another variable and call it location to.
Make sure it is also instance editable and show 3D widget.
Then we want to create a new variable and call this speed.
Change this barrel, type to be a flute and make this instance editable and then go compile.
So this bead is basically going to represent how long it takes for our moving platform to move between
location one and location two.
Finally, we want to head over to the construct and script and then drag in our interpreter movement
and just drag up here and look for set control points.
And there's one second point.
Just drag off this and look for make array.
Connect these nodes and then add two pins.
So zero and one.
Then just drag off the zero and look for make inter control point.
Then hook up on location one and connect there.
So I'll tell you what we've just done.
So we've just dragged in our to movement and we are manually setting the control points within it.
So we're making this first control point, our location one variable, and we're going to make the second
control point our location to variable.
So drag off one and look for me.
Enter to control point and drag and location to.
Finally to try and touch the movement and look for set duration.
And connect all speed variable.
So this will control how long it takes for our moving platform to move between location one and location
two.
We can now go compile and test this all out.
So if I scroll down, track in a moving platform and move it to layer 20.
I'm just going to delete my standard platform when I select my viewing platform.
We should see this three D gizmo called Location two.
Just move it anywhere.
So I'm going to move.
Let's see here.
Then let's look at one and let's say just leave it here.
Then if we go over to speed, let's make it two.
So take 2 seconds to move between these two points.
And now if I go play.
When I play my game, my platform is moving between those two points and I should be able to jump on
it.
Like this.
Nice.
With this, we have made our moving platform.